taylormorrison.com 2013-06-07

# Privacy Policy - Taylor Morrison

**Privacy Policy** : Taylor Morrison, Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively referred to as " **Taylor Morrison** ") provide information to the homebuying public, REALTORS®, other real estate brokers, trade partners and other users of the Internet regarding Taylor Morrison's communities, homes, financial services and other related products and services through the Web Site at www.taylormorrison.com (the " **Web Site** "). Your privacy is important to us, as well as to our respective subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, " **we** ," " **us** " or " **our** ") and we are committed to protecting the privacy of its customers and potential customers. To demonstrate this commitment, Taylor Morrison has created this Web Site privacy policy (the " **Privacy Policy** ") governing Taylor Morrison's use of the information that is collected through the Web Site. By accessing and viewing the Web Site, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy shall apply only to individual consumers and solely to information collected by this Web Site. 

**Updates to this Policy** : This Policy might change over time in Taylor Morrison's sole discretion. The most recent version of this Policy will be posted here. 

**About this Policy** : This Policy describes the privacy practices only on the websites and mobile phone applications where it appears. This policy explains the practices of all our brands, which include Taylor Morrison, Darling Homes* and others. Please note that Taylor Morrison and/or its affiliates may have separate privacy policies concerning information obtained through means other than the Web Site. In addition, this Policy does not apply to the practices of Taylor Morrison Home Funding, LLC (" **Taylor Morrison Home Funding** "), which maintains a separate privacy policy. For a copy of the Taylor Morrison Home Funding Privacy Policy, please click _here_ : **_*Note: While the Privacy Policy for Taylor Morrison's Darling Homes-Dallas and Darling Homes-Houston Divisions, collectively, are also contained herein, please refer to their respective separate Privacy Officer Contact Information below._**

Collection of Information: Even if you do nothing during your visit to the Web Site other than browse through the Web Site and read the information contained on the web pages, Taylor Morrison will nevertheless gather certain information about your visit automatically. This information does not identify you personally, but may, for example, reflect how you found or were directed to or used the Web Site. In addition, you may at your option provide personal identification or other information through the Web Site (for example, by way of your explicit request that Taylor Morrison send you requested information via e-mail or regular mail). It is possible, too, that your REALTOR®/Real Estate Agent may provide us with personal information concerning you or the Taylor Morrison communities and homes in which you are interested. 

Taylor Morrison gathers your IP address when you use any portion of the Web Site. Taylor Morrison also collects the name and URL of the Web Site that you visited immediately preceding your visit to the Web Site. Taylor Morrison uses this information on an aggregate basis to better understand Taylor Morrison's prospective customers and homebuyers, and Taylor Morrison may disclose this information to business and trade partners on an aggregate basis. Taylor Morrison also uses "cookies" to store your preferences in order to make your use of the Web Site more productive. Cookies are small files created by Web Sites that reside on your computer's hard drive and store information about your use of a particular web site. 

This Web Site utilizes browser cookies to advertise to our Web Site's prospects across the Internet. We collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information about your visits to our Web Site and your interaction with our products and services. The anonymous information is collected through the use of a pixel tag, which is industry standard technology used by most major web sites. No Personally Identifiable Information is collected during this process. If you do not want taylormorrison.com to collect this information, you may opt out of the service at any time. Opting out will not in any way affect your use of our Web Site. To Opt-out, please click here. In addition, you may opt out at any time by clicking on the link found in any of our e-mailed communications sent based on your prior request or by contacting our Privacy Administrator as indicated below. 

**Disclosure and Use of Information** : Taylor Morrison uses your contact information to respond to your requests for information or service, for general record-keeping purposes and to otherwise contact you about promotions and available products or services or, in unlikely circumstances, to contact you regarding product recalls. More specifically, Taylor Morrison may use your contact information to mail you Taylor Morrison's newsletter, Neighbor to Neighbor, or other promotional material or notification of special offers. Using your contact information, Taylor Morrison may also send you e-mail messages under the following circumstances, among others: 

  * to respond to an inquiry or request for information;
  * to thank you for contacting Taylor Morrison;
  * to welcome you to Taylor Morrison and to its products and services;
  * to explain new product offerings and features of our services;
  * to notify you of special promotions;
  * to communicate with you after the purchase of a home about your home and your use of our related services; and
  * to contact you after the purchase of a home regarding warranty services

Taylor Morrison does not sell, rent, share or otherwise disclose mailing lists or other personal information obtained through the Web Site to or with any non-affiliated companies. However, your contact information may be available or provided to third-party service providers and contractors (such as the Web Site developer) that are contractually obligated to protect your information as disclosed in this Privacy Policy. In order to maintain accurate records concerning communications that Taylor Morrison may have received from or sent to you, Taylor Morrison may also indefinitely store any information that you provide to Taylor Morrison through the Web Site. 

**Requests for Services** : You may request information regarding specific Taylor Morrison' communities, homes, financial services and other related products and services through the Web Site by submitting the requested contact information. You may not, however, purchase a home or any service directly through the Web Site. Any home warranty service request submitted through the Web Site is merely a request for a Taylor Morrison representative to contact you regarding such services. 

**Requests for Mortgage Information** : You may request information regarding the availability of home mortgage programs offered by Taylor Morrison Home Funding through the Web Site by submitting the requested contact and financial information. Any information you submit to the Web Site in connection with your request for mortgage information will be forwarded directly to the appropriate Taylor Morrison Home Funding affiliate, which will respond to your request or have a representative of Taylor Morrison Home Funding contact you. Taylor Morrison will not use or disclose the information you submit through the Web Site in connection with a request for mortgage information to any party other than Taylor Morrison Home Funding. _Please refer to the separate Privacy Policy for Taylor Morrison Home Funding_. 

**Third-party Web Sites** : The Taylor Morrison Web Site contains references to products of other companies and links to other web sites, including Web Sites that are not maintained or controlled by Taylor Morrison. The links to those other web site are placed for your convenience only, and do not comprise any warranty or endorsement on the part of Taylor Morrison as to the companies, products, services, information or programs associates with these Web Sites. Similarly, Taylor Morrison makes no warranty or endorsement of non-affiliated companies and products that appear on this Web Site. Taylor Morrison is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other web sites, and you are encouraged to review their privacy policies and terms of use. The fact that a link to a third-party web site exists on the Taylor Morrison Web Site does not mean that the third-party site operates under the same or similar privacy practices as set forth in the Taylor Morrison Privacy Policy. 

**Security Precautions** : Taylor Morrison takes precautions to protect data and information under its control from misuse, loss or alteration. Taylor Morrison' security measures include industry-standard technology and equipment to help protect your information, and Taylor Morrison maintains security measures to allow only the appropriate personnel and contractors access to your information. Unfortunately, no system can ensure complete security, and Taylor Morrison disclaims any liability resulting from use of the Web Site. 

**Notification of Changes** : If Taylor Morrison changes its Privacy Policy, the changes will be posted on the Web Site. If at any time Taylor Morrison decides to use or disclose a user's personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, Taylor Morrison will notify affected users by e-mail. Taylor Morrison will otherwise use and disclose a user's personally identifiable information in accordance with the Privacy Policy that was in effect when such information was collected. 

**Exceptions** : Other than as set forth above, Taylor Morrison will not otherwise use or disclose any of your personal information except to the extent reasonably necessary to: (i) process your information and to correct technical problems and malfunctions in the Web Site or the computer systems supporting the Web Site; (ii) protect the security and integrity of the Web Site; (iii) protect the rights and property of Taylor Morrison and others; (iv) take precautions against liability; (v) respond to claims that your information violates the rights and interests of third-parties; (vi) respond to judicial or administrative process or otherwise comply with applicable law; and (vii) to assist law enforcement agencies in connection with investigations or matters related to public safety. 

**Changes to Your Information:**

**TAYLOR MORRISON COMMUNITIES (OTHER THAN THE DARLING HOMES COMMUNITIES):** You may change or update information you previously provided to Taylor Morrison by contacting the Taylor Morrison Sales & Marketing Department via e-mail at [ webmaster@taylormorrison.com](mailto:webmaster@taylormorrison.com) or regular mail at Corporate Office 4900 N. Scottsdale Road, Suite 2000 Scottsdale, AZ 85251 480-840-8100. 

**DARLING HOMES COMMUNITIES ONLY** : You may change or update information you previously provided to Darling Homes by contacting the Darling Homes Division's Privacy Officer by e-mail at [legal@darlinghomes.com](mailto:legal@darlinghomes.com) or via telephone at (469) 252-2200 or by regular mail addressed to Privacy Officer, Darling Homes Dallas, 2500 Legacy Dr # 100, Frisco, TX 75034 or Darling Homes Houston, 10255 Richmond Ave # 150, Houston, TX. 

**TAYLOR MORRISON HOME FUNDING** : You may change or update information you previously provided to Taylor Morrison Home Funding by visiting the _Taylor Morrison Home Funding's Privacy Policy_. 

**Stopping E-mails and Promotional Materials:**

**TAYLOR MORRISON COMMUNITIES:** You may elect to "opt out" of the Taylor Morrison e-mail system by affirmatively choosing to do so at <http://www.taylormorrison.com/OptOut.aspx>. You may also stop e-mail messages and other promotional mailings by contacting the Taylor Morrison Privacy Officer by e-mail at [privacy_officer@taylormorrison.com](mailto:privacy_officer@taylormorrison.com) or by regular mail addressed to Privacy Officer, Taylor Morrison, 4900 N. Scottsdale Road, Suite 2000 Scottsdale, AZ 85251 or via telephone at (480) 840-8100. Please visit the Taylor Morrison Home Funding's Privacy Policy to opt out of Taylor Morrison Home Funding emails and promotional material. 

**DARLING HOMES DIVISION** : You may elect to "opt out" of the Darling Homes' Division e-mail system by contacting the Darling Homes Division's Privacy Officer by e-mail at [legal@darlinghomes.com](mailto:legal@darlinghomes.com) or via telephone at (469) 252-2200 or by regular mail addressed to Privacy Officer, Darling Homes-Dallas Division, 2500 Legacy Dr # 100, Frisco, TX 75034 or Darling Homes-Houston Division, 10255 Richmond Ave # 150, Houston, TX. 

TAYLOR MORRISON HOME FUNDING: Please visit the  _Taylor Morrison Home Funding's Privacy Policy_ to opt out of Taylor Morrison Home Funding emails and promotional material. 

**Questions or Comments:**

**TAYLOR MORRISON COMMUNITIES** : Questions or comments concerning this Privacy Policy may be directed to the Taylor Morrison Privacy Officer by e-mail at [ privacy_officer@taylormorrison.com](mailto:privacy_officer@taylormorrison.com) or by regular mail addressed to Privacy Officer, Taylor Morrison, 4900 N. Scottsdale Road, Suite 2000 Scottsdale, AZ 85251 or via telephone at (480) 840-8100. 

**DARLING HOMES COMMUNITIES** : Questions or comments specifically concerning this Privacy Policy (as it relates to the Darling Homes Division only) may be directed to the Darling Homes Privacy Officer by e-mail at [ legal@darlinghomes.com](mailto:legal@darlinghomes.com) or via telephone at (469) 252-2200 or by regular mail addressed to Privacy Officer, Darling Homes-Dallas Division, 2500 Legacy Dr # 100, Frisco, TX 75034 or Darling Homes-Houston Division, 10255 Richmond Ave # 150, Houston, TX. 

TAYLOR MORRISON HOME FUNDING: For any questions or comments specifically concerning the Taylor Morrison Home Funding Privacy Policy, please visit the _Taylor Morrison Home Funding's Privacy Policy_

Respecting and protecting customer privacy is vital to Taylor Morrison Home Funding's business. By explaining the Taylor Morrison Home Funding Privacy Policy to you, we trust that you will better understand how we keep our customer information private and secure while using it to serve you better. Keeping customer information secure is a top priority, and we are disclosing our policies to help you understand how we handle the personal information about you that we collect and disclose. This notice of the Taylor Morrison Home Funding Privacy Policy explains how you can limit our disclosing of personal information about you. The provisions of this notice will apply to former customers as well as current customers unless we state otherwise. Please refer to the terms and conditions of the separate Privacy Policy maintained by our affiliate Taylor Morrison, Inc., which is also found on this Web Site. 

The Taylor Morrison Home Funding Privacy Policy explains the Following:

  * Protecting the confidentiality of our customer information.
  * Who is covered by the Taylor Morrison Home Funding Privacy Policy.
  * How we gather information.
  * The types of information we share, why, and with whom.
  * Opting Out - how to instruct us not to share certain information about you or not to contact you.

Protecting the Confidentiality of Taylor Morrison Home Funding's Customer Information: We take our responsibility to protect the privacy and confidentiality of customer information very seriously. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal standards to store and secure information about you from unauthorized access, alteration, and destruction. Our control policies, for example, authorize access to customer information only by individuals who need access to do their work. 

From time to time, we enter into agreements with other companies to provide services to us or make products and services available to you. Under these agreements, the companies may receive information about you but they must safeguard this information, and they may not use it for any other purposes. 

Who is Covered by the Taylor Morrison Home Funding Privacy Policy: We provide our Privacy Policy to customers when they conduct business with our company. If we change our privacy policies to permit us to share additional information we have about you, as described below, or to permit disclosures to additional types of parties, you will be notified in advance. This Privacy Policy applies to consumers who are current customers or former customers. 

How Taylor Morrison Home Funding Gathers Information: As part of providing you with financial products or services, we may obtain information about you from the following sources: 

  * Applications, forms, and other information that you provide to us, whether in writing, in person, by telephone, electronically, or by any other means. This information may include your name, address, employment information, income, and credit references;
  * Your transaction with us, our affiliates, or others. This information may include your account balances, payment history, and account usage;
  * Consumer reporting agencies. This information may include account information and information about your credit worthiness;
  * Public sources. This information may include real estate records, employment records, telephone numbers, etc.

Information Taylor Morrison Home Funding Shares: We may disclose information we have about you as permitted by law. We are required to or we may provide information about you to third-parties without your consent, as permitted by law, such as: 

  * To regulatory authorities and law enforcement officials.
  * To protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud, unauthorized transactions, claims, or other liability.
  * To report account activity to credit bureaus.
  * To consumer reporting agencies.
  * To respond to a subpoena or court order, judicial process or regulatory authorities.
  * In connection with a proposed or actual sale, merger, or transfer of all or a portion of a business or an operating unit, etc.

In addition, we may provide information about you to our service providers to help us process your applications or service your accounts. Our service providers may include billing service providers, mail and telephone service companies, lenders, investors, title and escrow companies, appraisal companies, etc. 

We may also provide information about you to our service providers to help us perform marketing services. This information provided to these service providers may include the categories of information described above under "How We Gather Information" limited to only that which we deem appropriate for these service providers to carry out their functions. 

We do not provide non-public information about you to any company whose products and services are being marketed unless you authorize us to do so. These companies are not allowed to use this information for purposes beyond your specific authorization. 

Opting Out: We also may share information about you within our corporate family of office(s). We may share all of the categories of information we gather about you, including identification information (such as your name and address), credit reports (such as your credit history), application information (such as your income or credit references), your account transactions and experiences with us (such as your payment history), and information from other third parties (such as your employment history). 

By sharing this information we can better understand your financial needs. We can then send you notification of new products and special promotional offers that you may not otherwise know about. For example, if you originally obtained a mortgage loan with us, we would know that you are a homeowner and may be interested in hearing how a home equity loan may be a better option than an auto loan to finance the purchase of a new car. 

You may prohibit the sharing of application and third-party credit-related information within our company or any third-party company at any time. 

Note for Joint Accounts: Your Opt Out choices will also apply to other individuals who are joint account holders. If these individuals have separate accounts, your Opt Out will not apply to those separate accounts.

Changes to Your Information: You may change or update information you previously provided to Taylor Morrison Home Funding by contacting us via e-mail at [ tmhfprivacy_officer@taylormorrisonhf.com](mailto:tmhfprivacy_officer@taylormorrisonhf.com), or by regular mail at TMHF's Corporate Office at Taylor Morrison Home Funding, 151 Southhall Lane Suite 250, Maitland, FL 32751 

Stopping E-mails and Promotional Materials: You may elect to "opt out" of the Taylor Morrison Home Funding e-mail system by affirmatively choosing to do so at http://www.taylormorrison.com/OptOutTMHF.aspx. You may also stop e-mail messages and other promotional mailings by contacting the Taylor Morrison Home Funding Privacy Officer via e-mail at [ tmhfprivacy_officer@taylormorrisonhf.com](mailto:tmhfprivacy_officer@taylormorrisonhf.com), regular mail addressed to TMHF Privacy Officer, Taylor Morrison Home Funding, 151 Southhall Lane Suite 250, Maitland, FL 32751 or by calling us at 407-660-0090. 

Taylor Morrison Home Funding is licensed in the following states:

ARIZONA  |    |    |     
---|---|---|---  
Taylor Morrison Home Funding, LLC  |  9000 E. Pima Center Pkwy; Suite 350A, Scottsdale, AZ 85258  |  Arizona Mortgage Banker  |  MB License # 0916681 NMLS Company ID #149227; Branch ID #157431 Responsible Individual Patrick James Saturno MLO #257912   
CALIFORNIA  |    |    |     
---|---|---|---  
Taylor Morrison Home Funding, LLC  |  81 Blue Ravine Road, Suite 117, Folsom, CA 95630  |  CA Department of Corporations Residential Mortgage Licensing Act  |  CA DOC RMLA License #4131114 NMLS Company ID #149227; Branch I.D. #377334 Patrick James Saturno, Branch Manager MLO #257912   
Taylor Morrison Home Funding, LLC  |  8105 Irvine Center Drive, Suite 1450A, Irvine, CA 92618  |  CA Department of Corporations Residential Mortgage Licensing Act  |  CA DOC RMLA License #4131114 NMLS Company ID #149227; Branch I.D. #979640 Patrick James Saturno, Branch Manager MLO #257912   
COLORADO  |    |    |     
---|---|---|---  
Anna J. Custard dba Taylor Morrison Home Funding, LLC  |  1420 W. Canal Court, Suite 170 Littleton, CO 80120  |  Colorado Mortgage Company Registration  |  LMB100017625 (MB) CF-989574 Branch 001; NMLS Company ID #149227; Branch ID #347943, Anna J Custard MLO #273250   
FLORIDA  |    |    |     
---|---|---|---  
Taylor Morrison Home Funding, LLC  |  151 Southhall Lane, Ste 200A, Maitland, FL 32751  |  Florida Mortgage Lender  |  FL ML License #MLD72 NMLS Company ID #149227 Branch ID #886579   
Taylor Morrison Home Funding, LLC  |  551 North Cattleman Road, Suite 200A, Sarasota, FL 34232  |  Florida Mortgage Lender  |  FL ML License #MLD72 NMLS Company ID #149227 Branch ID #379919   
TEXAS  |    |    |     
---|---|---|---  
Taylor Morrison Home Funding, LLC  |  5353 W. Sam Houston Parkway, Suite 190 Houston, TX 77041  |  Texas - SML Mortgage Banker Registration  |  NMLS Company ID #149227; Branch ID #336785 Laura Kunzweiler MLO #241627   
Taylor Morrison Home Funding, LLC  |  11200 Lakeline Blvd, Ste 150C, Austin, TX 78717  |  Texas - SML Mortgage Banker Registration  |  NMLS Company ID #149227; Branch ID #885815 Christina Lynne Ferro MLO #269639   
  
Questions or Comments: If you have any questions or comments regarding the Taylor Morrison Home Funding Privacy Policy , your questions and comments may be directed to the Taylor Morrison Home Funding Privacy Officer by contacting us via e-mail at [ tmhfprivacy_officer@taylormorrisonhf.com](mailto:tmhfprivacy_officer@taylormorrisonhf.com), regular mail addressed to TMHF Privacy Officer, Taylor Morrison Home Funding, 151 Southhall Lane Suite 250, Maitland, FL 32751 or by calling us at 407-660-0090.
